LE THANH TUNG

Test Leader



Thông tin

🗂 Jan 23, 1993

Male

★ Hanoi, Vietnam

·

Skills

Test skills

Smart TV

Computer

Powerpoint

Soft skill

Negotiation

Interests

Football, music, beer

Objective

Take advantages of test skills & experience and understanding software process, test technical to become a professional tester and bring a lot value to company. From that, I will contribute to development of Company not only as a tester.

Work experience

Test lead

July 2019 - Present

VinID Company

Main responsibilities:

- Create test plan, sprint report for each sprint
- Test API, mobile, web (iOS, Android, Chrome)
- Review product requirement, UI/UX
- Creating and reviewing test documents (test case, test report, bug)
- Control task, issue, effort for each member
- Discuss with customer, partners about business, issue...
- Raising as well as solving whenever a problem occurs
- Suggest solutions, ideas for PO/BA to resolve issues about product
- Summarizing and reporting to PM and test manager about working status, testing progress, test result, issue for each sprint

Feature

- General trader lending (create bank account, register lending account)
- CASA linking (create bank account, link bank as payment account)
- Wallet (Link bank, unlink bank, fund in, fund out)
- Check out (payment by wallet, linked bank, napas)
- Group fund
- Money transfer

Test lead

June 2018 - June 2019

FPT Software

Main responsibilities:

- Planning and implementing test activities with different test target
- Managing and monitoring a testing team with 5 members
- Analyzing requirement, creating and reviewing test documents such as: test policy, test design, test case, test report, bug report
- Summarizing and reporting to customer as well as higher leader about working status, testing progress, test result, issue, etc.
- Raising as well as solving whenever a problem occur
- Develop requirement (create test viewpoint, function list, test design, test case and checklist)
- Manage test document, configuration (Network, server, broadcast environment)
- Review test reports, bug lists and log bugs
- Support members when they met issues and find the
- Communicate, discussing with customer about bug, issue or $\ensuremath{\mathsf{Q\&A}}$ about requirement

Product: Smart TV (Android OS)

Sub-lead

Sep 2017 - May 2018

Main responsibilities:

- Develop requirement for new mobile app (create test design, check list and test case)
- Review test report
- Control execute test progress of test team
- Communicate, discussing with customer, dev team about bug, issue, improve requirement...

Product: Mobile app

Test member

Aug 2015 - Sep 2017

FPT Software

Main responsibilities:

- Develop document for new mobile app (create test design, check list and test case)
- Execute test

Product: Smart TV

Activities

Captain

July 2019 - Present

VinID football club

- Organize tournament

Member

June 2021 - Present

Union Corporation

- Organize music event

Honors & Awards

10/2020: 1st Speed Up We Are One

08/2019: 2nd Vingroup Football Tournament

/2018: The quality hero at business unit

10/2017: 1st FPT 13/9 Football CUP

Education

FPT University

Oct 2011 - Dec 2015

Major: Software engineer

GPA: 6.6/10